S-Su-won... Quickly, call a doctor!
ス スウォン 早く 医務官を
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
King Il will not wake again.
イル陛下はもう目を開けません
I killed him.
私が殺しました
What are you talking about?
何を言って
Y-You're not the kind of person who would do this.
あ あなたはそんな事 出来る人じゃ...
You don't know how I have lived for this day.
あなたは知らない 私がこの日の為に生きてきた事を
Episode 2:
Torn Bonds
It's too quiet.
やけに静かだ
Then no one has noticed yet?
では また誰一人 気付いてないのだな
No, sir.
はい
賓客も文官達も皆 宴の酒に酔い
正体なく眠り込んでいます
The honored guests and civil officials are all drunk from the party and fast asleep.
I see.
そっか
Only General Hak's movements are cause for concern.
ハク将軍の動きのみが気掛かりですが
Who is cause for concern?
だれが気掛かりだって
Why don't you tell me in detail?
聞かせて貰おうか 詳しく
Wh-Why?
な なぜ
My father cared for you since you were a child.
父上はあなたを幼い頃からとても可愛がって
You're right.
そうですね
I loved King Il too.
私もイル陛下が大好きでしたよ
Even though people whispered that
he was a coward who feared conflict,
争いを恐れる臆病者だと囁かれてる
I used to believe he was just kind.
それが陛下の優しさなのだと以前は信じていました
However, I was wrong.
でもそうではなかった
That wasn't the case.
そうではなかったんです
Do you remember my father, Yu-hon?
私の父 ユホンを覚えていますか
My uncle?
伯父上
Ever since my father was young,
he was courageous and intelligent.
父上は幼少期より勇猛果敢で利発
He grew into a warrior
who always led our armies to victory.
成人して軍を率いれば常に勝利を収め
Everyone wanted him to become the next king,
and no one doubted that he would.
誰もが次期国王となる事を望み それを疑わなかった
However, ten years ago,
だが十年前
先王ジュナムがこの高華王國の王に選んだのは
the former king, Ju-nam, chose not my father, but Uncle Il, as King of Kouka.
父ユホンではなく伯父のイルでした
No one understood his choice.
皆理解出来なかった
The eldest son was the rightful successor to the throne,
王位継承権は長男にあるのに
so why did he choose the weak Il?
なぜ軟弱なイル様をお選びになられたと
But my father kept smiling.
しかし 父上はいつも笑っていました
The throne is no big deal to me.
王座など俺には些末事
俺は弟を守り民を守る為に前線で戦い続けようぞ
I will continue to fight on the front lines to protect my younger brother and my people.
I was proud of my father and respected him greatly.
私はそんな父上を誇り 深く敬愛した
Someday, I hoped to stand alongside him on the battlefield and offer my life to him.
何時か共に戦場に立ち
この命を父上の為に捧げようと思っていたのに
But after succeeding the throne,
王位に就いた後
for reasons unknown, King Il killed Yu-hon, his own brother.
ある御事かイル陛下は実の兄であるユホンを殺害したのです
No. My uncle died in an accident.
そんな 伯父上は事故で...
That's the official story.
表向きはそうですね
But King Il stabbed my father
to death with a sword.
けれど父上はイル陛下に剣で刺されて亡くなった
Do you understand?
分かりますか
King Il, who was thought to hate weapons and avoid conflict,
武器を嫌い争いを避けていたはずのイル陛下が
killed my father with a sword.
父上を剣で殺したのです
No. It's not true.
嘘 そんなの 嘘
It is the truth.
それが真実です
I have avenged my father, and as his successor, in flesh and in spirit,
父上の敵を討ち
父上の遺志を受け継ぐ者として私はこの高華の王となる
I will become King of Kouka.
It's not true.
嘘
This is a dream, a nightmare.
これは夢 悪い夢よ
だってスウォン...
After all, Su-won,
you smiled so kindly...
あなたはあんなり優しく笑って
I love your hair, Yona.
私は好きですよ ヨナの髪
...when you gave me this hair ornament.
簪を この簪をくれたじゃない
I wasn't expecting you to be awake in the middle of the night.
あなたがこんな真夜中に起きていたのは誤算でした
I had heard you hardly ever visited the king's quarters.
陛下の部屋にも滅多に立ち寄らないと聞いていたのに
Why did you come, Princess Yona?
なぜ来たのです ヨナ姫
I wanted to tell him...
伝えたくて
I wanted to tell my father
that I could never forget you.
私は...スウォンを忘れる事は出来ないと...父上に...伝えたくて
Lord Su-won.
スウォン様
Kei-suk.
ケイシュク
Everything is ready.
準備 全て整いました
You have achieved your long-cherished desire.
本懐を遂げられたのですね
Did Princess Yona see you?
まさか ヨナ姫に
This will make things quick.
ならば話は早い
Kill her, Lord Su-won.
殺してお仕舞いなさい スウォン様
Silence the princess.
姫の口を封じるのです
Su-won?
スウォン
Put it out! We don't want to draw any attention!
消せ 騒ぎ気取られてはまずい
Yes, sir!
捕まえてください
Seize her.
Yes, sir!
はい
Who... Who was that person?
誰 あの人は誰
That person who killed my father
and who is trying to kill me...
父上を殺し私を殺そうとするあの人は
is not Su-won!
スウォンじゃない
He is not my beloved Su-won!
私の大好きなスウォンじゃない
Prepare yourself, Princess.
お覚悟 姫様
This is for the Kingdom of Kouka.
これも高華国の為なのです
Did he hate me?
私は憎まれていたの
Since we were young, I...
幼い頃からずっと...
I only ever loved Su-won.
ずっとスウォンだけだったのに
I didn't ask for much.
多くを望んだ訳じゃない
As long as I could see Su-won's smile, I was happy.
スウォンの笑顔が見られれば それでよかったのに
スウォン
Su-won!
I knew Lord Su-won was here tonight,
so I was trying to stay out of your way.
今夜はスウォン様がいらっしゃいるから
邪魔者は遠慮したつもりだったんですがね
見張りだったはずの守備隊はここに勢揃いしてるし
The guards who were supposed to be on watch are all gathered here.
There are people I don't recognize too.
見知らぬ輩も嫌がりますし
What is the meaning of this?
これは一体どう言う事ですか
Well, Lord Su-won?
なぁ スウォン様
H-Hak?
ハ ハク
I'm sorry for leaving your side, Princess Yona.
お側を離れて申し訳ありません ヨナ姫様
Hak...
ハク
Hak, are you here for me?
ハクは私の見方
The king told me to protect you.
俺は陛下からあんたを守ると言われる
No matter what happens,
何があろうと俺は
I will obey his orders!
それに絶対服従する
控えよ下郎
Withdraw, servant.
You are standing before King Su-won, the new master of Hiryuu Castle.
今より緋龍城の主となったスウォン陛下の御前なるぞ
Who's the master of what, now?
誰が何の主だって
I have a bad feeling about this, but I must ask.
どうも嫌な予感がするんですがね
スウォン様 イル陛下はどこにおられる
Lord Su-won, where is King Il?
I just sent him to hell.
私が先程 地獄へ送って差し上げた
Are you drunk?
酒にでも酔っておいでか
That's going too far, even for a joke.
戯言にしては度が過ぎます
Ask Princess Yona.
ヨナ姫に聞いみるといい
She confirmed the king's death with her own eyes.
その目で王の死を確かめられたのだから
Tell the truth!
真実を言え
I'm not lying.
偽りではありません
Su-won! You are telling me
that you killed your king?
スウォン 国王を弑逆したと
You killed our kind king?!
お前が あの優しい王を
スウォン様
Lord Su-won...
下がっていなさい
Stay back.
If you get any closer, you'll lose your head.
近付けば首が飛びますよ
The man standing before you is Son Hak.
目の前に居るのはソンハクです
This man is...
この男が
Yes. He is the heart of Castle Hiryuu and one of the five generals:
そう 彼はこの緋龍城の要 五将軍の一人
the Thunder Beast of Kouka.
高華の雷獣
Su-won, why? Are you trying to usurp the throne?
スウォン 何故だ 王位の簒奪か
No, you wouldn't fixate on that kind of thing.
いや お前はそんな物に執着する奴じゃないだろう
Did you turn your sword on our kind king,
who detested weapons?
武器を厭う心優しき王に刃を向けたのか
Your pride allowed that?!
テメエの誇りがそれを許したの
Kindness?
優しさか
This kingdom has no need for a weak king!
か弱き王など この国には必要ない
ソンハク
Son Hak...
He is grandson of Son Mun-deok, former head of the Wind Tribe.
風の部族の前族長 ソンムンドクの孫であり
He rose to lead the tribe at a young age.
若くして族長の座を就いた男
A single blow from his blade is like lightning,
その大刀での一撃は稲妻の様であり
高華の雷獣とも異名を持つ
earning him the nickname
"The Thunder Beast of Kouka."
That's enough!
そこまでだ
Lay down your weapon, Thunder Beast.
武器を抛け 雷獣
Lord Su-won, are you all right?
スウォン様 ご無事ですか
Su-won...
スウォン
Was the Su-won I knew just an illusion?
俺が見ていたスウォンは幻だったのか
I thought I could entrust you with the princess.
お前になら 姫を任せてもいいと思っていた
Fool.
愚かな 五将軍の一人と言えと 所詮はまだ若い
You may be one of the five generals,
but you are still young.
なに
What?
At this rate, the Kingdom of Kouka will fall into ruin before long.
高華王国はこのままでは時を迂闊 滅亡する
For you and Princess Yona, who have indulged in peace at Castle Hiryuu,
緋龍城で安念を貪ってきたあなたやヨナ姫に
there is no way to understand
Lord Su-won's feelings-
スウォン様のお心を推し量る事など...
Quiet, Kei-suk.
口を慎みなさい ケイシュク
What does that mean?
どう言う意味だ
The Su-won you know never existed.
貴方達の知っていたスウォンは最初から居なかったんです
Should anyone get in my way,
I will cut him down,
道を阻む者があれば切り捨てます
no matter who he is.
誰であろうと
I don't want to hear this.
聞きたくない
I don't want to hear any more of this.
もう 何も聞きたくないの
Wh-What?
After them! Don't let them escape!
護衛 逃がすな
Yes, sir!
はい
This way, General Hak!
こちらです ハク将軍
Did you take that terrible shot, Min-su?
お前か ミンス さっきの下手くその矢は
姫様を連れて付いてこい 離れるなよ
Take the princess and follow me.
Don't fall behind.
Y-Yes, sir.
はい
Out of the way!
退け
This way!
こちだ
はい
Yes, sir.
ハク将軍 後ろへ
General Hak, behind you!
We should find somewhere to hide.
一先ず 何処かに身を隠そう
You're right.
そうですね
Let's go.
行くぞ
Yes, sir.
はい
切りがないですね
There's no end to them.
Princess, is King Il really dead?
姫様...イル陛下は本当に亡くなられたのですか
I see.
そうですか
I'm sorry. I simply couldn't believe it.
申し訳ありません どうしても信じられなくて
Until just a while ago, he was smiling so happily about your birthday.
つい先程まで 姫様のお誕生日だと
幸せそうに笑っていらっしたのに
It's only a matter of time until they find us.
見つかるのも時間の問題だな
The soldiers that Lord Su-won brought here,
城内にはスウォン様が率いてきた兵と
スウォン様を支持する兵が集まりつつある
along with the guards loyal to him, are gathering within the castle.
If we're caught, they'll definitely kill us.
捉まれば間違いなく殺される...か
Yes.
はい
I'll secure an escape route for you.
私が逃げ道を確保します
You two must escape from the castle.
お二人はこの城から脱出して下さい
But you...
だがお前は
Don't worry about me.
I promise I'll get away.
ご心配なく 必ず逃げっ切って見せます
They're around here somewhere! Find them!
この辺りいるはずだ 探せ
Yes, sir!
はい
Six soldiers in front of the rear gate.
裏門の前に兵が六人
More waiting in ambush.
伏兵も...
Min-su, you...
ミンス お前
I'll draw them after me.
私が引き付けます
You use that opportunity to escape.
その隙に脱出を
Princess, take care.
姫様
どうか ご無事で
There she is!
居たぞ
あっちだ
She's over there!
Don't let her escape!
逃がすな
Min-su...
ミンス
姫さん 早く
Princess, hurry!
There she is! This way!
居たぞ こっちだ
Princess... King...
姫様...陛下...
They seem to have escaped into the mountains.
裏山の方に逃げた様です
I will organize a party to search the area immediately.
直ちに山狩り隊を組織致します
ハク将軍は峻険な山里 風牙の都の育ち
General Hak was raised in the precipitous mountain village of Capital Fuuga.
Even if he has the princess with him,
姫を連れているとは言え
it will be difficult for the men
of the castle to find them.
城の者達では発見は難しいでしょう
Princess Yona,
ヨナ姫
少し休みますか
should we rest a while?
Is Min-su dead?
ミンスは死んじゃったの
Am I also going to die?
私も死ぬのかな
Is Su-won going to kill you too?
ハクもスウォンに殺されて
あんなくそったれにやる命何て持ち合わせねでぇですよ
I don't have a life to give
to that piece of crap.
Please don't die, Hak.
死なないでね ハク
If you die, I won't forgive you.
死んだら...許さない...から
I still can't believe it.
まだ信じられねぇな
I can't believe King Il died...
イル陛下が死んだ何て
and left the princess alone.
姫を一人にして
You good-for-nothing king.
しょうもねぇ王様だよ
Su-won...
スウォン
I'm sorry.
申し訳ありません
I had them comb the mountains all night, but they still haven't found anything.
夜通し山狩りを行わせてはいるのですが 未だ
How are things inside the castle?
城内の様子は
People are beginning to notice something is wrong, and unrest is growing.
次第に異変を察知し騒ぎが広まりつつあります
General Ju-doh, what's going on?
ジュド将軍一体何か
Is this the work of insurgents?
賊の仕業なのか
We're investigating the matter as quickly as we can.
急ぎ調べを進めています
What should we do, Lord Su-won?
如何なさいますか スウォン様
Let's go, Princess. Our pursuers are coming.
行きましょう姫様  追手が来る
Where are we going?
どこへ 行くの
During the party, even though my father was crying tears of joy,
私 宴の時 父上が泣いて喜んでいたのに
I didn't utter a single word of thanks to him.
一言も言わなかったわ ありがとうって
Where am I supposed to go now,
なのに 父上を置いて どこへ
leaving my father behind?
どこへ行くと言うの
Hak...
ハク
We'll go anywhere we have to, as long as it means you'll live.
どこへでも行きますよ あんたが生き延びられるなら
That is how you can return the king's feelings.
それが陛下への思いの返し方です
My sixteenth birthday...
十六歳の誕生日
That night,
あの夜
I lost my family, my home,
and the people I loved.
私は家族を 帰る場所を 思い人を 沢山な事を失った
And then, I had the encounters
that led me to the present.
そして今に繋がる出会いがあった
What is that?
あれは？
Fire!
打て
何者だ
Who are you?
また新た敵
A new enemy!
大人しく去る この高華国から
Depart quietly...
from the Kingdom of Kouka!
この国を好きにはさせない
I won't let you run amok in this kingdom!
Damn you.
己
What?
なに
私は生きる
I will live...
亡き父上の思いに 仲間達に 報いる為に
to repay my late father's love
and my friends' kindness!
wakaru kai
Do you see
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
The same obscure lyrics and background
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
I've always talked ideals
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
Like supporting others
姫さん あんたが生きる為に俺を使う
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
I hope you don't realize too early
俺はその為にここに居る
次回 暁のヨナ 第三話
hayasuginai you ni
How irresponsible I was being with my words
遠い空
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
Since my hands are warmer than others'
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
When I hold your hand
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
Next Time
Princess, use me to stay alive.
That is what I'm here for.
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona,
episode 3:
Episode 3:
The Distant Sky
The Distant Sky.